<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ClimAlert</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_call">S.O.S.</string>
    <string name="title_info">Tips</string>
    <string name="title_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>

    <string name="text_calor_extremo">Extreme heat</string>
    <string name="text_granizo">Hail</string>
    <string name="text_tormenta_invernal">Winter storm</string>
    <string name="text_tornado">Tornado</string>
    <string name="text_inundacion">Flood</string>
    <string name="text_incendio">Wildfire</string>
    <string name="text_terremoto">Earthquake</string>
    <string name="text_tsunami">Tsunami</string>
    <string name="text_avalancha">Avalanche</string>
    <string name="text_lluvia_acida">Acid rain</string>
    <string name="text_erupcion_volcanica">Vulcanic eruption</string>
    <string name="text_gota_fria">Cold drop</string>
    <string name="text_tormenta_electrica">Thunder storm</string>

    <string name="title_prevencion">Prevención</string>
    <string name="title_que_hacer">Qué hacer (o consejos)</string>
    <string name="title_senales_insolacion">Señales de insolación</string>
    <string name="title_congelacion">Congelación</string>
    <string name="title_hipotermia">Hipotermia</string>

    <string name="text_calor_extremo_desc">Extreme heat is defined as much higher summer temperatures or much more humid conditions than average. This extreme heat can cause heat stroke, which is a condition characterized by nausea, vomiting, headache, heat of the skin, drowsiness, drowsiness, and disruption of muscle fibers exposed to its effects. This is caused by the fact that the body does not have the capacity to cool itself adequately.</string>
    <string name="text_granizo_desc">Hail is a type of solid precipitation that is composed of irregular balls or lumps of ice, each of which is referred to as a hailstone. It is formed mainly of water ice and its size can vary between 5 and 50 millimeters (0.19 and 1.968 inches) in diameter, and even exceed that size.</string>
    <string name="text_tormenta_invernal_desc">A winter storm is precipitation of snow on the earth\'s surface that also includes intense winds.</string>
    <string name="text_tornado_desc">Tornadoes are violently spinning columns of air that extend from a thunderstorm to the ground. Tornadoes can destroy buildings, flip cars and create deadly wind-driven debris.</string>
    <string name="text_inundacion_desc">Floods are temporary overflows of water onto land that is normally dry. They can result from rain, snow, coastal storms, storm surges, dam overflows and other water systems. They can cause power outages, disrupt transportation, damage buildings and create landslides.</string>
    <string name="text_incendio_desc">A wildfire is a fire that spreads uncontrolled in forest or wild land, affecting plant fuels, flora and fauna. It is distinguished from other types of fire by its wide spread, the speed with which it can spread from its place of origin, its potential to change direction unexpectedly, and its ability to overcome obstacles such as roads, rivers, and firebreaks.</string>
    <string name="text_terremoto_desc">An earthquake is a sudden and rapid shaking of the ground caused by the displacement of subway rocks deep below the earth\'s surface. Earthquakes can cause fires, tsunamis, landslides or avalanches.</string>
    <string name="text_tsunami_desc">Tsunamis, also known as seismic waves, are a series of huge waves created by underwater disturbances such as earthquakes, landslides, volcanic eruptions or meteorites.</string>
    <string name="text_avalancha_desc">An avalanche is a huge amount of snow that slides rapidly down the mountain, usually on slopes of 30 to 45 degrees. When an avalanche stops, the snow solidifies like concrete and people become trapped. People trapped in avalanches can die from suffocation, trauma or hypothermia.</string>
    <string name="text_lluvia_acida_desc">Acid rain is one of the consequences of atmospheric pollution. It is precipitation containing both water and toxic residues, mainly acidic, from industrial emissions and other types of machinery, such as vehicles. This acidification of soil and surface water has devastating effects on ecosystems and poses a serious danger to living beings.</string>
    <string name="text_erupcion_volcanica_desc">A volcano is an opening in the earth\'s crust that allows molten rock, gases and debris to escape to the surface. A volcanic eruption can involve lava and debris that can move at speeds of up to 100 mph, destroying everything in its path. Volcanic ash can travel for hundreds of miles and cause serious health problems.</string>
    <string name="text_gota_fria_desc">According to the State Meteorological Agency, a cold drop or DANA (Isolated High Level Depression) is a large mass of low temperature air that has separated from a polar jet. This, being in areas of warmer weather, interacts with the air of higher temperature in the area and causes storms of all kinds and meteorological instability, and can cause, among other things, winds of up to 100 km / h. It is more common in coastal areas near warm waters, since the moisture-laden air rising from these warm seas favors the formation of these cold drops when it meets the polar jets.</string>
    <string name="text_tormenta_electrica_desc">Lightning is one of the leading causes of injury and death from weather hazards. Although most lightning victims survive, people struck by lightning often manifest a number of long-term debilitating symptoms. Thunderstorms are dangerous storms that include lightning and can create or cause powerful winds in excess of 50 mph (80 km/h), hail, flash flooding and/or tornadoes.</string>

    <string name="lista_prevencion_extremo">Calor extremo</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_granizo">Granizo</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_tormenta_invernal">Tormenta invernal</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_tornado">Tornado</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_inundacion">Inundación</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_incendio">Incendio</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_terremoto">Terremoto</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_tsunami">Tsunami</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_avalancha">
        <li>Obtener equipo adecuado para protegerse de lesiones en la cabeza y crear espacios de aire.</li>\n
        <li>Aprender primeros auxilios para poder brindar tratamiento a los demás.</li>\n
        <li>Usar casco para minimizar lesiones en la cabeza.</li>\n
        <li>Usar una bolsa de aire para avalanchas.</li>\n
        <li>Llevar sonda colapsable de avalanchas y una pala pequeña para ayudar a rescatar a otras personas.</li>\n
    </string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_lluvia_acida">Lluvia ácida</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_erupcion_volcanica">Erupción volcánica</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_gota_fria">Gota fría</string>
    <string name="lista_prevencion_tormenta_electrica">Tormenta eléctrica</string>

    <string name="lista_que_hacer_extremo">Calor extremo</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_granizo">Granizo</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_tormenta_invernal">Tormenta invernal</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_tornado">Tornado</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_inundacion">Inundación</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_incendio">Incendio</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_terremoto">Terremoto</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_tsunami">Tsunami</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_avalancha">
        <li>Obtener equipo adecuado para protegerse de lesiones en la cabeza y crear espacios de aire.</li>\n
        <li>Aprender primeros auxilios para poder brindar tratamiento a los demás.</li>\n
        <li>Usar casco para minimizar lesiones en la cabeza.</li>\n
        <li>Usar una bolsa de aire para avalanchas.</li>\n
        <li>Llevar sonda colapsable de avalanchas y una pala pequeña para ayudar a rescatar a otras personas.</li>\n
    </string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_lluvia_acida">Lluvia ácida</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_erupcion_volcanica">Erupción volcánica</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_gota_fria">Gota fría</string>
    <string name="lista_que_hacer_tormenta_electrica">Tormenta eléctrica</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="button">Button</string>
    <string name="google">GOOGLE</string>
    <string name="prefs_file">863788857384-1fuvh34n2o9j8t92b0ips2u3ra57scgu.apps.googleusercontent.com</string>
    <string name="Token_Id">AIzaSyBp9uSKVgoEIIfva6pWU6M03A6b_E4Wlgk</string>

</resources>